Akarsh Bachu

Data Scientist

Skilled in Data Science, ML, DL and Python with 3 years of experience, Achievements include creating C-CNN model which can classify 25000 merchants from noisy transaction data, it's utilized in campaigns which in turn boosted revenue of our organization.



bachu.akarsh@gmail.com

7729862404

Hyderabad, India

akarsh.netlify.com

linkedin.com/in/akarshbachu in

github.com/akarshbachu

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Data Scientist Cardlytics Inc.

05/2020 - 07/2020

Description/Responsibilities

- · Cardlytics is into Purchase Intelligence, Based on transactions data from banks we generate offers and these offers are placed on bank application, these are customized at individual user level.
- We get transaction data as a string of 15 pipe separated fields which is noisy, Cleaning this data using Machine Learning and Deep Learning techniques.
- · Extracting merchant names from the transaction data and mapping it to a valid brand name using the C-CNN model.
- Mapping this transaction data to store location at various confidence levels like street, zip, and city-level using Auto Encoders, K-Means & Google Maps API.

Jr. Data Scientist & Java Dev ADP India Pvt Ltd

07/2018 - 07/2020

Description/Responsibilities

- Description: The Product Provides Analytics of various other Products of ADP, Using Dashboards, KPI's (Key Performance Indicators) Benchmarks and Explorers.
- Involved in all phases of Data Science and ML tasks like Data Preprocessing, EDA, Visualization, Feature Engineering, Developing Models and Validation.
- · Recommending insights based on the user interaction, Used Random Forest classifier to classify insights as liked or disliked i.e. converted recommendation problem to classification problem.
- · Performed Machine Learning tasks to predict the turnover of an employee, achieved AUC of 0.88 using XGBoost.
- Creating KPI's (Key Performance Indicators) using Java and JPA Framework(myBatis)
- Developing API's in Java for Insights data fetch & Feedback Mechanism

EDUCATION PGD In Data Science

IIIT Bangalore 07/2019 - 07/2020

3.83/4

B.Tech

Mahatma Gandhi Institute of Technology

09/2013 - 05/2017

Course Computer Science and Engineering

74%

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Stock Price Prediction (05/2019 - 05/2019)

It's a Deep Learning Model, that predicts the stock price of (n+1)th day given n days data using LSTM.

Donors Choose Application Screening (11/2018 - 12/2018)

It's a Classification problem where our model classifies if the project proposed can be Approved or not, Achieved an AUC of 0.74 using LightGBM.

Netflix Movie Recommendation Engine (08/2018 - 08/2018)

 It's a Machine Learning Model that recommends the movies by analyzing user's previous history.

StackOverFlow Tag Predictor (07/2018 – 07/2018)

 It's a Machine Learning Model, that predicts the suitable tags for the Description/Question given. Achieved precision of 80% and hamming loss of 0.002 using Linear SVM.

Amazon Review Classification (04/2018 - 04/2018)

It's a Machine Learning project, where the model classifies the reviews as Positive or Negative.

Personal Website (02/2018 - 02/2018)

It's a Personal Portfolio created using HTML and Bootstrap, includes a Chat-bot (Virtual Representation of Me).

Heart Connoisseur (05/2016 - 06/2016)

It's an IOT based alarming device built for detecting heart abnormalities that also notifies the pre-chosen contacts for help in the span of an SMS.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Oracle Certified Java Programmer Oracle Testing Id: OC1731881 (Java SE 8)

Hackerrank Algorithm Level 5

Received a Merit certificate from ICSI for presenting 'Heart Connoisseur'(IOT product)